# Jim Newpower

# Software Engineer

2757 S Langley Ct Denver CO 80210 jimnewpower@gmail.com 303<u>.870.4369</u>

Engineer with over 25 years of experience in the software industry. Dedicated developer with diverse skill set and creativity who delivers reliable software through test-driven and agile methods. Proficient in multiple languages and frameworks, excelling in small, collaborative teams.

Expert in Java API (through version 10), including all of the latest enhancements (streams, lambdas, multithreading, etc.).

## **Qualifications**

- ° Java, C/C++, C#, SQL, Python, PHP, HTML/CSS, Javascript, UML
- ° .NET, Swing, Android, Web
- ° Git, Visual Studio, Eclipse, Android Studio, Gerrit, Jenkins,

Rally, Jira, Enterprise Architect

° JUnit, Apache Commons, Guava, Jide, OpenGL

- ° Multithreading/Parallel Processing
- ° Computational Geometry, Numerical Analysis
- ° Database transaction/management system
- ° Agile, Test Driven, Clean Code, SOLID
- ° Big data analysis, statistics, Monte Carlo
- ° ACM and IEEE member

# **Experience**

#### 2008-Present: Platte River Associates, Inc.

Software Engineering Director

- ° Architect and develop flagship geologic modeling applications
- ° Analyze big data with statistics, histograms, radar charts, cross plots, regression, etc.
- ° Manipulate and visualize large scientific datasets from seismic surveys/well logs
- ° Leverage multicore for simulations, large datasets, visualization, etc.
- ° SQL database back-end
- ° Implement Gridding and Contouring algorithms
- ° Import and export well known file types for ArcGIS, Petrosys, Zycor, Surfer, etc.
- ° Work with clients and stakeholders to continually improve software

#### 2010-Present: Prima Technologies, Ltd.

Founder and Principal Engineer

- ° Android internals contract to improve Android OS modification for Spectralink handhelds
- ° Barcode scanner, SIP, Push to Talk
- ° EliteDraft Android fantasy football draft application (over 13,000 unique installs)
- ° Manage live drafts, push draft picks to website for live updates/analysis

#### 1993-2008: Platte River Associates, Inc.

Software Engineer

- ° Develop and maintain existing software
- ° Implement new graphics system
- $^{\circ}$  Ports: Linux to Windows, 16 to 32-bits, C to C++, C++ to Java

#### **Achievements and Interests**

Sponsored 2 Senior Software Engineering projects at University of Colorado:

- ° Seeing Another Dimension (SAD), a 3-D visualization application
- ° Sparkle Magic API for Graphics (SMAG), a pure Java 2-D graphics system
- ° Family time
- ° Skiing
- ° Hiking
- ° Photography
- ° Cooking
- ° Building things

### **Education**

Bachelor of Science Computer Science (Engineering) University of Colorado 1992

- ° Computer Performance Modeling
- ° Artificial Intelligence, Computer Architecture
- ° Electrical Engineering, Algorithms
- ° Software Engineering Senior Project
- ° Calculus I,II,III, Physics, Probability & Statistics
- ° Data Structures, Graphics, Languages